A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Photographs FA738
Rockefeller Archive Center
- General, Program, and Project Photographs, 3
  - Resources and the Environment (R&E), 3_15
    - Beartooth Mountain, photograph by George Silk, TIME/Life, 1971 (Box 99, Folder 1794)
    - Biological Control of Agricultural Pests, 1971 (Box 99, Folder 1795)
    - The Conservation Foundation, 1971 (Box 99, Folder 1796)
    - Four Corners Power Plant, New Mexico, 1971 (Box 99, Folder 1797)
    - New Hampshire, Conservation and Pollution - John Karol photographs, 1973 (Box 99, Folder 1798)
    - Rainbow Bridge, National Park Service (Box 99, Folder 1799)
    - Tilton School, New Hampshire, Water Pollution Study by Students, 1970 (Box 99, Folder 1800)
    - University of British Columbia, Canada, Advanced Research in Ecology and Resource Management, Gulf islands Project, 1970 (Box 99, Folder 1801)
    - University of Western Ontario, Canada, Early School Environment Study, 1970 (Box 99, Folder 1802)
  - Science and Engineering (SE), 3_16
    - California Institute of Technology, Development of Graduate Program in Mathematics, 1963 (Box 100, Folder 1803)
    - Case Institute of Technology, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 1804)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1962 (Box 100, Folder 1805)
    - Dartmouth University - Engineering Design, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 1806)
    - Engineering Residencies, 1965 (Box 100, Folder 1807)
    - Harvard University - Soil Mechanics, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 1808)
    - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1965 (Box 100, Folder 1809)
    - Load Testing of New York World's Fair Structures, Building Research Advisory Board, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 1810)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Mechanical Engineering, 1960s (Box 100, Folder 1811)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Special Summer Sessions (Box 100, Folder 1812)
    - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY, 1965 (Box 100, Folder 1813)
    - Scripps Institute of Oceanography, 1959 (Box 100, Folder 1814)
    - Western Reserve University, Program in Biological Sciences, 1960s (Box 100, Folder 1815)
    - Oceanography Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, MA, 1965 (Box 100, Folder 1816)
    - Tulane University Advanced Graduate Program in Mathematics, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 1817)
    - University of Toronto - Engineering, 1963 (Box 100, Folder 1818)
    - University of Wisconsin, Briotron Plans, 1964 (Box 100, Folder 1819)
    - University of Wisconsin - research in Atmospheric Sciences, Development of Personnel, 1960 (Box 100, Folder 1820)
    - Yale University - Astrograph, Lick Observatory, 1960 (Box 100, Folder 1821)
  - Miscellaneous, 3_17
    - 42nd Street Redevelopment, New York City (Box 100, Folder 1822)
    - Ammel Park Housing Project, San Francisco, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 1823)
    - Bayoud Palm Disease, press release photographs (Box 100, Folder 1824)
    - Peter Buttonweiser, City High Schools, 1982 June (Box 100, Folder 1825)
    - Center for Legal and Social Studies (CELS), Argentina, Emilio Mignone, 1983-1984 (Box 100, Folder 1826)
    - Community Development Corporations (CDCs) - photo feature (Box 101, Folder 1827)
    - "Corrective Capitalism: The Rise of America's Community Development Corporations", 1987 (Box 101, Folder 1828)
    - Costal Enterprises, Maine (Box 101, Folder 1829)
    - "Cross Section" booklet photographs (Box 101, Folder 1830)
    - Danforth Foundation Conference, 1969 (Box 101, Folder 1831)
    - "A Decent Place to Live" photographs (Box 101, Folder 1832)
    - Duke University - Institute of Policy Sciences and Public Affairs, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 1833)
    - East Central Committee for Opportunity (ECCO) (Box 101, Folder 1834)
    - Edison Institute - Building and Restoration of Wayside Inn, South Sudbury, MA, 1957 (Box 101, Folder 1835)
    - "Energy: The Next 20 Years", Joint Press Conference, Ford Foundation and Rockefeller Foundation, Washington DC, 1979 September 17 (Box 101, Folder 1836)
    - European Institute of Business Administration (INSEAD), 1971 (Box 101, Folder 1837)
    - Exploratorium, San Francisco, 1975 (Box 101, Folder 1838)
    - Film stills - "Are You Listening: Household Technicians", 1977 (Box 101, Folder 1839)
    - Film stills - "Changing Work", 1975 (Box 101, Folder 1840)
    - Film stills - "The Erie Environment", 1977 (Box 101, Folder 1841)
    - Film stills - "Indian Rights, Indian Law", 1978 (Box 101, Folder 1842)
    - Film stills - "Learning About Thinking, And Vice Versa", 1971 (Box 101, Folder 1843)
    - Film stills - "That Our Children Will Not Die", 1978 (Box 101, Folder 1844, 1845)
    - Film stills - "Tomorrow We'll See What Happens", 1973 (Box 102, Folder 1846)
    - Film stills - "they Call It Wildcat", 1974 (Box 102, Folder 1847)
    - Film stills - "Turning Around: A Look at Neighborhood Housing Services", 1974 (Box 102, Folder 1848)
    - Film stills - "Vera and the Law", 1975 (Box 102, Folder 1849)
    - Ford Foundation Assistance to Puerto Ricans, 1975 (Box 102, Folder 1850)
    - Ford Foundation Field Office, Mexico City, 1965 (Box 102, Folder 1851)
    - Ford Foundation Field Office, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, 1965 (Box 102, Folder 1852)
    - Ford Foundation Headquarters Building, New York, LIFE magazine photographs by John Zimmerman, 1968 March 19 (Box 102, Folder 1853)
    - Ford Foundation Headquarters Building, New York - Garden Christmas Carol Singing, 1969 (Box 102, Folder 1854)
    - Ford Foundation Headquarters Building, New York - Library Staff, 1970s (Box 102, Folder 1855)
    - Ford Foundation Headquarters Building, New York - Misc. architectural and office interior photographs, 1970s (Box 102, Folder 1856)
    - Ford Foundation - Misc. photographs of officers and staff, 1980s (Box 102, Folder 1857, 1858)
    - Ford Foundation - Media and Law conference, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 1859)
    - Ford Foundation Photo Library, 1964-1967 (Box 102, Folder 1860)
    - Ford Foundation Publications Catalog photographs, 1970s (Box 102, Folder 1861)
    - Ford Foundation - Retirement Party for McGeorge Bundy (prints), 1979 (Box 102, Folder 1862)
    - Ford Foundation - Retirement Party for McGeorge Bundy (negatives), 1979 (Box 102, Folder 1863)
    - Ford Foundation-related political and editorial cartoons, 1968-1980 (Box 103, Folder 1864)
    - "Ford Foundation at Work" by Dick Magat, photographs, 1978-1980 (Box 103, Folder 1865)
      Includes news clippings and correspondence.
    - "Four Minorities and the PhD", photographs, 1973 (Box 103, Folder 1866)
    - "The Future for India's Scientifically Prepared Engineers", photographs, 1970 (Box 103, Folder 1867)
      Includes reports and correspondence.
    - Eli Giuzberg, Columbia University (Box 103, Folder 1868)
    - Dr. Roy Greep, Harvard University, 1969 (Box 103, Folder 1869)
    - Robin Hanbury-Tenison, Indonesia, 1979 (Box 103, Folder 1870)
    - "History of the Ford Foundation", for new staff, prepared by John English, 1980-1989 (Box 103, Folder 1871)
    - Hunter College, New York - Centro de Estudios Puertorriquenos, 1985 (Box 103, Folder 1872)
    - Indochinese Refugees (Box 103, Folder 1873)
    - International African Institute (IAI), London - West African Museum s Project, Weaving Exhibits, 1984 (Box 103, Folder 1874)
    - "International Program of the Ford Foundation" booklet photographs, 1973 (Box 103, Folder 1875)
    - International Research and Exchange Board (IREX), 1979-1980 (Box 103, Folder 1876)
    - Jazzmobile, 1983 (Box 103, Folder 1877)
    - Holy Names College Music Training - Kodaly Laboratory School, Oakland, CA, 1970s (Box 103, Folder 1878)
    - Dr. Katherine Kuder photographs, Family Planning, India, 1955-1970; Kuder, Katherine (Box 141, Folder 1991)
      Includes: 1. Intrauterine Devices (IUDs) used in various countries/regions (shown actual size); 2. Certificate of appreciation presented to Dr. Kuder, 1971 May; 3. VIII All India Obstetric and Gynecological Congress, Bombay 1955, group photograph including Dr. Kuder (back row, ninth from left).
    - Dr. Katherine Kuder photographs, Family Planning, India, 1950s-1960s; Kuder, Katherine (Box 103, Folder 1879A, 1879B, Box 136, Folder 1968)
    - Dr. Katherine Kuder, State Family Planning Conference, Rajasthan, Jaipur (India), photograph album, 1965 March 6-8; Kuder, Katherine (Box 104, Folder 1880)
    - Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation - "Supported Work", 1978-1979 (Box 104, Folder 1881)
    - "Matters of Choice: A Ford Foundation Report on Alternative Schools" photographs, 1974 (Box 104, Folder 1882)
    - McGraw-Hill Film, "The Game", "Merry Go Round" (Box 104, Folder 1883)
    - Meadbourne Primary, film stills (Box 104, Folder 1884)
    - Miller Center - Daniel Grogan photography, 1983 (Box 104, Folder 1885)
    - "Minding the Children" photographs (Box 104, Folder 1886)
    - "Minorities in Business: Ford Foundation Assistance, 1965-1975", photographs, 1976 (Box 104, Folder 1887)
    - Minority Enterprise Small Business Company (MESBIC) and Interracial Council for Business Opportunity (ICBO) press conference, 1970 December 7 (Box 104, Folder 1888, 1889)
    - Mutual Real Estate Investment Trust (MREIT) (PRI), clippings, 1968 (Box 104, Folder 1890)
    - National Public Radio (NPR), 1985 (Box 104, Folder 1891)
    - "The New Teacher: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance for New Patterns in Education of Teachers" photographs, 1962 (Box 104, Folder 1892, Box 136, Folder 1973)
    - New York State Constitutional Convention - Interns, 1967 (Box 104, Folder 1893)
    - "Nine for Equality Under the Las: Civil Rights Litigation" photographs, 1976 (Box 105, Folder 1894)
    - North Carolina Dance Theater, 1983 (Box 105, Folder 1895)
    - North Carolina Fund Photography Exhibit - Billy Barnes photographs (captions) (Box 105, Folder 1896)
    - North Carolina Fund Photography Exhibit - Billy Barnes photographs (prints) (Box 105, Folder 1897)
    - North Carolina Fund Photography Exhibit - Billy Barnes photographs (negatives) (Box 105, Folder 1898)
    - Office of Reports - Requests for reprints / photographs used in Annual Reports, publications, etc. (Box 105, Folder 1899)
    - "Poor Women in Poor Lands", exhibition layout, diagrams, captions, etc., 1981 (Box 105, Folder 1900)
    - "Poor Women in Poor Lands", exhibition photographs, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 1901)
    - "Program Related Investments: A Different Approach to Philanthropy" booklet photographs, 1974 (Box 106, Folder 1902)
    - Project Redirection (teenage pregnancy) (Box 106, Folder 1903)
    - QUASAR, Magnet Middle School Holyoke, MA, 1995 (Box 106, Folder 1904)
    - Bill Ravanesi photographs, 1981-1982 (Box 143, Folder 1995)
      19 color prints, 11x14.
      See also: Ford Foundation grants, Foundation-Administered Project (FAP), 08290200 (PA82-200): URBAN POVERTY-SMALL GRANT ACTIONS IN UNITED STATES AND INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS PROGRAM, 1981-1983 (Reel 4414).
    - Bill Ravanesi photographs, "The Hidden Holyoke A Cityscape and Its People" correspondence and news clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 144, Folder 1996)
    - Bill Ravanesi photographs, "The Hidden Holyoke A Cityscape and Its People" photographs, 1982 (Box 144, Folder 1997)
      7 color prints, 16x20.
    - Bill Ravanesi photographs - "The Holyoke Project", Funeral of Firefighter Raymond Finn, 1982 January (Box 106, Folder 1905)
    - Bill Ravanesi photographs - "Workers on the Land: West/Southwest", 1983-1985 (Box 106, Folder 1906)
    - Solar Energy, 1970s (Box 106, Folder 1907)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, 1979 (Box 106, Folder 1908)
    - "Tapestry for Tomorrow" photographs, Middle East and Africa report, 1964 (Box 106, Folder 1909)
    - "Teachers of Tomorrow" (TFAE publication), photographs, 1955 (Box 106, Folder 1910)
    - "That 51 percent" photographs, 1974 (Box 106, Folder 1911)
    - "Two African Patterns" photographs (Box 106, Folder 1912)
    - United Nations, High Commissioner for Refugees, photographs, 1982-1983 (Box 106, Folder 1913)
      Misc. general photographs of refugees.
    - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), various grants (Box 106, Folder 1914)
      Includes photographs documenting Ford Foundation grants 06300228, 07700315, and 07450664 (PA63-228, PA77-315, PA745-664) for 1977 Annual Report.
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, 1979 (Box 106, Folder 1915)
    - Vera Institute of Justice, Bowery Project, New York City, 1966 (Box 106, Folder 1916)
      Includes photographs of the Vera Institute's 48-bed detoxification / alcoholism treatment center on the Bowery in New York City.
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1957 (Box 106, Folder 1917, Box 107, Folder 1918, 1919)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1961 (Box 137, Folder 1981)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1963 (Box 107, Folder 1920)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1964 (Box 107, Folder 1921, 1922, Box 139, Folder 1984)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1967 (Box 107, Folder 1923, 1924, Box 139, Folder 1985, Box 108, Folder 1925, 1926)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1968 (Box 108, Folder 1927)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1970 (Box 108, Folder 1929, Box 139, Folder 1986)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1971 (Box 108, Folder 1930)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1972 (Box 108, Folder 1931)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1973 (Box 108, Folder 1932)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, 1975 (Box 108, Folder 1933)
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, undated (Box 108, Folder 1934)
      Misc. photographs used in Ford Foundation Annual Reports.
    - Ford Foundation Annual Report photographs, undated (Box 146)
    - Milburn Lincoln Wilson photographs, Trip to India, 1952-1953 (Box 109, Folder 1935, 1936, 1937)
      Milburn Lincoln Wilson (Director of the United States Extension Service at the U.S.D.A.) and his wife Ida, made two trips to India (in 1952-1953 and 1957-1958), at the invitation of Douglas Ensminger, the Ford Foundation?s Representative in India. The photographs in these files depict training programs in various Indian states, among other subjects. Countries and regions visited include: Rome, Greece, Turkey, Turkey Village trip, Iraq, Pakistan, Amritsar, India; Delhi, India; Punjab, India, Bophali, India; Hyderabad caves, India, Lucknow, India; Wiser trip, India; Allahabad, India; Agra, India, Taj Mahal and Fatehpur Sikri, Agra, India, Patna, Bihar, India, Jordan, Lebanon, Burma, Bangkok, Indonesia, Philippines, Japan, Hawaii.
    - Milburn Lincoln Wilson photographs, Trip to India, 1957-1958 (Box 109, Folder 1938, 1939, 1940, 1941)
      Milburn Lincoln Wilson (Director of the United States Extension Service at the U.S.D.A.) and his wife Ida, made two trips to India (in 1952-1953 and 1957-1958), at the invitation of Douglas Ensminger, the Ford Foundation?s Representative in India. The photographs in these files depict training programs in various Indian states, among other subjects. Countries and regions visited include: Rome, Athens, Lebanon, New Delhi, India, Orientation village, India; Punjab, India; Lucknow, India; Poona (Pune), India; Etawah village, India; Bombay milk plant; Jaipur, India; Kajauraho, India; Gwalior, India; Patna, India; Madras, India; Mysore, India; Hyderabad, India; New Delhi, India; Greece, Rome, Germany, Holland.
    - Unidentified photographs (Box 110, Folder 1942, 1943, 1944, 1945)
    - Ford Motor Company 100th Anniversary memorabilia and publications, 2003 (Box 133)
    - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), "Sowing the Green Revolution" publication photographs, 1970 (Box 134, Folder 1946)
    - American Working Class History Project (CUNY) (Box 134, Folder 1957)
    - Asian Productivity Organization and Japan Productivity Center photograph album - Small Business Management Trainers and Consultants Course, 1964-1965 (Box 134, Folder 1958)
    - Atlanta University, 1953 (Box 135, Folder 1959)
    - Biological Pest Control photographs for news release (Box 135, Folder 1960)
    - Certificates and Awards presented to the Ford Foundation, 1970s-1980s (Box 135, Folder 1961)
    - Children's Television Workshop, 1970s (Box 135, Folder 1962)
    - "Community Development Corporations: A Strategy for Depressed Urban and Rural Areas" publication photographs, 19703 (Box 135, Folder 1963)
    - The Electric Company, 1971 (Box 135, Folder 1964)
    - "Give a Damn" and "Who Says Things Are Changing?" advertisements The 1967 Equal Employment Opportunity magazine campaign (Box 135, Folder 1965)
    - "The Good Seed", "The Difference It Makes" publication photographs (Box 135, Folder 1966)
    - "A Richer Harvest" publication photographs (Box 136, Folder 1976)
    - "Skills, Scholarship, and the Public Service" publication photographs (Box 136, Folder 1977)
    - "That Our Children Will Not Die" film stills (Box 136, Folder 1978)
    - "Theatre Reawakening" publication photographs (Box 136, Folder 1979)
    - "Context the World" publication photographs (Box 137, Folder 1980)
    - Unidentified Photographs (Box 138)
    - The Greater New York Fund Gold Merit Award, for Outstanding Community Service, Presented to the Employees of the Ford Foundation, 1968 (Box 140, Folder 1987)
    - Unidentified Photographs (Box 140, Folder 1988)
    - "Sharps and Flats" publication photographs (Box 141, Folder 1989)
    - International Institute for Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Ibadan, Nigeria - Architectural renderings (Box 141, Folder 1990)
    - "Golden Years?" publication photographs (Box 142, Folder 1992)
    - "Roots of Change: The Ford Foundation in India" publication photographs (Box 142, Folder 1993)
    - Educational Television (ETV) program photographs (Box 142, Folder 1994)
    - Innovations in State and Local Government - Winners, 1992, 1994, 1995; 16x20 color photographs. (Box 148)
      File Plan
      Former box ID 41004.
    - Board of Trustees Confidential Directory (mechanicals), 1989 (Box 146)